Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH .srt FiLES!
Fire!
- 11:00!
- Fire!
Fighter plane to the bow!
- 12:00! 12:00! Fire!
- 12:00! 12:00!
- Brace for impact!
- Damage report!
Fire party to the bow.
Damage report now!
Japs blew the crap out of us
at Pearl harbor.
We cowboyed up,
turned the tables on them.
Ain't a whole lot of quit
in them either.
Gave as good as they got.
Iwo jima, okinawa.
- Where's this all going?
- Mainland ground invasion's
only going to stretch
this war out even longer.
Truman's in his third month
as president.
Honeymoon's about over.
America wants this war
to end and quickly.
Jesus, are you talking
about the atomic bomb?
Send a message
loud and clear.
Drop it right on Hiroshima,
military target.
Ostensibly, yes.
But you'll kill every man,
woman, and child,
not to mention
the radioactive fallout.
Even if the bomb works,
and there's no guarantee
that it will,
you can't fly it to Japan.
We motorboat the son of a bitch.
The tinian, philippine sea.
With all due respect,
we know their Navy's
stretched thin,
but the Japanese
will spot a fleet.
Not a fleet.
No escorts.
One ship, a fast ship.
Alone, unprotected.
That's a damn
suicide mission.
But if it works...
They're heroes.
Who do you have in mind?
"There will always be war
until we kill off
our own species.
The difference
between us and them
is that we want to
do our duty and then go home.
The man who flew his kamikaze plane
into the bow of our ship
knew he wasn't going home.
He was on
a suicide mission
using his body
as ammunition.
God help all of us
when we face an enemy like that."
"In a few days
it's my birthday.
My best gift would be
just to see you again,
my dear Louise."
Yeah.
- Paul?
- Sir.
Can you please get this off
to western union?
Aye aye, sir.
So you been
sweet on this girl
since the fourth grade and
you ain't asked her out yet?
You don't get it.
A sophisticated debutante
like her, hell,
you wouldn't know
what I mean.
You have to prove yourself.
That's why I got to get
that promotion...
What, so she wouldn't
like you without a promotion?
While you're plotting
and planning,
you know what's happening
out there?
Life!
So live it, my friend.
Holy smokes!
Daddyo's
got big pockets.
Brian smithwick.
Judge bazemore.
How are you, sir?
This here
is my friend Mike.
Hell of a place
you got here, sir.
I was telling my boy bama,
it's like that movie,
"frankly, my dear,
i don't give a damn."
Oh, forget it.
Mike d'Antonio.
Good to meet you.
He's from New York, sir.
Brian, why don't you step
into my office?
There's a gentleman there
who would like to meet you.
Alonso, show Mike
up to the parlor,
and tell those girls
to turn down that racket.
Brian, is it true we might
be finally invading Japan?
Well, that has been
the rumor now for a while, sir.
They don't really tell us much.
I've heard we have crippled
the Japanese imperial Navy.
Well...
Much in large part to the men
of the USS Indianapolis.
Hear, hear!
Do you think the war's
going to continue, son?
I don't really know, sir.
Do you have a son
in the military?
Heavens no, son.
He's got money in steel.
That's right,
war is good for business,
and business
is good for America.
- We're proud of you, son.
- Thank you, sir.
Five, six, seven, eight!
You girls ready?
Hey, could use
a little help over here!
No, no, you go ahead
and make a fool of yourself.
I'm fine right here.
Your friend is teaching
the dance society girls
the latest dance craze
from New York.
Not bad, huh?
Whoo!
He's a gas.
♪
All right,
i want to close on the ranks
of a damn Rolls-Royce,
all right?
She's the crown Jewel
of the Navy!
Good job.
Okay, we're gonna get this boat
looking brand-spanking new!
Let them japs know
they didn't hurt nobody!
They didn't do
nothing to us, okay?
Good job, sailors!
No holes in my shoes,
and no holes in my boat!
Hey, it's going to take two
surgeons six hours
to get my size-10 boot
out of your ass
if you don't
get a move on, fng.
Means "friggin' new guy."
- Sir.
- Carry on.
Congratulations, mcwhorter.
I heard the news.
- A boy right?
- Can't wait to meet him.
He's nine pounds and 13 ounces
of romping-stomping dynamite.
And the wife's fine, too.
Outstanding.
How we doing here?
The japs put a pretty
big hole in the ship,
but the big guns
are fine, sir.
Sir? Lieutenant standish
reporting for duty again, sir.
Ready to turn these sailors
into a lean,
mean fighting machine.
And may I say, my father,
admiral Percy standish,
sends his regards.
All hands stand by.
All hands, stand by.
Looks like you got
the damage from that zero
- repaired pretty quickly.
- Yes, sir.
We finished it today.
The fact that you lost
only nine men
is a solid testament
to you and your crew.
Nine too many.
Ready to get
out there again, captain?
Admiral,
i have nine new officers
and 250 new enlisted men,
but we will press through
workup and be ready for sea.
This way, this way.
Captain, president Truman
has chosen you
to lead a highly
classified mission.
This is not
a combat mission.
You will carry two pieces
of highly classified cargo
to tinian at best speed
stopping only at Pearl harbor
to refuel.
You leave tomorrow.
Where do we pick up
our escort?
Charlie, this mission could save
millions of American lives.
It is top-secret.
There'll be no escort.
Does this have something to do
with the Manhattan project?
Open that tomorrow
after you've weighed anchor.
As of 0500 tomorrow,
this ship is under
the direct command
of the president
of the United States.
Good luck, captain.
Get your butt outta my seat.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Look, look, look it,
that's that cracker
that's been messing with you.
You told everybody
you was gonna whup his ass.
What you gonna do?
What? Hey.
It's still a diamond.
I'll get her a better one
when I can afford it.
It's not about
the damn ring.
I can't believe you're
about to pop the question
in front of the judge.
You even thought about this?
You've known her three months.
I thought y'all
were just having fun.
Oh, yeah,
we're having lots of fun.
Besides, when you ever known
me to be scared of a judge?
You miss 100 percent...
Of the shots that you
don't take, yeah, I know.
Just don't forget to call them
"sir" and "ma'am," all right?
Hey, you're gonna be
our best man.
Mama, mama, yeah,
there we are.
You have no shot.
No shot.
Double or nothing.
Double or nothing!
I'm telling you,
kamikaze planes
coming down from everywhere,
you know?
And I'm firing back, see?
I'm like...
There's planes coming...
Hot damn, Sanchez,
you're cooking with gas!
♪ Ba, ba, ba, hey! ♪
♪ Ba, ba,
ba, hey! ♪
Tame your horses!
I'm coming! I'm coming!
Next round's on you...
How's a young fella gonna know
how much he can drink
unless he knows
how much he can't?
It's 1945.
Our ship is docked
in San Francisco for repairs.
The streets are alive,
and the sailors...
We're on the town tonight.
D'Antonio!
Daddy didn't mean it.
Yeah, well, it sure as hell
sounded like he did, Clara!
Please, wait!
Mike!
- D'Antonio!
- What?
- Would you stop and listen to me?
- I'm listening.
You need to give daddy a chance.
He just needs some time.
So you never told your parents
you were slumming it, I guess.
That's not what this is.
That's exactly
how they looked at me!
A feisty young lady in red
pursued a sailor...
While another one...
Seemed to pursue her.
Come on! Come on!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, hey.
Mess hall boy
knows about boxing.
They fighting!
Hey, y'all, they fighting!
That's not fair,
you can't hold that against me!
D'Antonio! D'Antonio!
There's a fight.
There's a fight!
- There's a fight!
- Stay right here.
- Mike!
Show him what for.
Which one of you wants
to get sliced open first?
You really need that thing?
I'm flattered.
Three against five.
Little friend here makes it even.
Garrison.
Maybe we shouldn't.
Shut up!
Shut up, Quinn!
Back up, boys.
I said back up now!
All right.
Fair fight.
You and me.
You don't know nothing
about fair.
You ain't on a ship now,
peckerwood.
If they move, cut 'em.
If you don't, I cut you.
Oh, yeah!
Come on, come on.
Get up get up!
Garrison,
it's not worth it!
Come on!
Yeah, knock him out, man!
Hey,
there's a fight down there!
I got the colored fella.
I got the colored.
- I got the colored.
- Get him, Garrison!
My money's
on the colored fella!
Soft face, boys!
Cut it out!
Back off! Back off!
Huh? I told you.
It's not worth it!
- Get him!
- Mike!
Smoke his ass!
Break it up!
Stand down!
Hey, listen up, listen up!
Where you going
with my money...
Hey, hey, hey,
we just got word okay?
Were shipping out,
captain's orders, okay?
We need to get back to the ship.
- Mike!
- Clara!
Clara!
What happens between us
is between us.
Clara, let's go.
I am not my father.
- And you really mean that?
- Yes.
D'Antonio!
D'Antonio, we got to hoof it!
- All right!
- No, no. No!
This isn't how
it was supposed to...
- I love you!
- I love you, too!
Now, sailor!
- Clara, let's go.
- I'll be back!
For those of you who are new
to the Indianapolis,
I am your captain.
Without me,
you are worthless.
You are my crew,
and without you,
i am worthless.
Our success,
our very survival...
Is contingent upon
our functioning together
as one cohesive unit.
We have the complete
confidence and trust
of the commander-in-chief,
as well we should.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir!
- Am I understood?
♪
The Indianapolis
is a heavy cruiser
designed to take out
enemy ships and aircraft,
but our guns are useless
against submarines.
That's why normally,
we are sent out with an escort
of destroyers in front of us
that act as blockers.
Their job is to detect
and destroy enemy subs
with depth charges
before they can get to us.
Many of the crew
are mere boys
with no idea of the danger
we face out here at sea.
If we are fired upon
by an enemy sub
and if miraculously
we spot it early enough,
we have at maximum four minutes
before the torpedo arrives.
Our main defense is to get
the ship watertight
point station zebra
so any hull rupture
doesn't spread and sink us.
For the secret mission,
we are in effect
a glorified postal service
delivering two packages
with no protection,
but mine is not to reason why.
Hey, w division
was seven seconds faster
than everybody else,
even without you.
Bullshit!
Hey, farm boy,
chew on that first.
Ah, eat that.
That's gold.
Yeah, you bastard.
Concerned about
submarines, sir?
Hard to hit
what you can't see.
If I may, protocol
would be to zigzag, sir.
Not so effective
against kaitens.
Kaitens?
It's a new Japanese weapon,
a manned suicide torpedo,
like an underwater
kamikaze plane.
If the enemy
fires a kaiten,
they can recalibrate
your position on the fly.
We're faster than their subs,
but not their kaitens.
General quarters.
Send it up, come on!
Move it!
- Battle stations!
Let's go! Let's go!
Load us up!
Let's go, let's go!
Man your stations!
Ready!
Down!
Ammo! Ammo!
- Go!
- Ready!
Fire, fire, fire!
Fire, fire, fire,
fire, come on!
Done!
Group w can stand down.
I want the big guns
running again in the dark.
W, drill is over.
Isolate the power in sectors
five, six, and seven.
You did it!
Run the test again.
All right.
All right, limp dicks,
cap says we go again.
Come on!
You swab it,
then you swab it again!
- If I had two of you...
- Hey!
Man, you are as dumb
as a bucket of bolts.
Hell, boy,
everybody know that.
Look here,
which one is standish's?
- Is it this one right here?
- No, no, no, that's mcvay's.
Okay.
Man, come on.
Ugh.
You are nasty.
Man, Quinn,
what are you doing?
- The right thing.
- That's too much. He's gonna know.
Hope he like the pie.
Captain?
Good work
on the guns today.
Thank you, sir.
What do you put in this
delicious pie, Theodore?
I'm afraid that's
classified information, sir.
Set it down, imbecile.
Yes, sir.
Is it too hot, sir?
It's 42 seconds
on the big guns, sir.
Four minutes
and 36 seconds on zebra.
- Run it again?
- Negative.
All ahead. Best speed.
All ahead, bendix.
She was a four at port,
but she was a 10 on the ship!
Y'all are really lucky
i cut my right cross today.
Doing what?
Changing your tampon?
Yeah, laugh it up, ya mug.
Okay, $75, deuce.
That's another 50
to Sanchez, right.
25 to Quinn.
Shit.
Anybody know
where we're going
after we drop cargo?
All right, chowder heads,
who took my bag?
Nobody took your bag,
you idiot.
Are you worth $850,
you shiny devil, huh?
Alpha, Romeo, tango.
Sir? Where are we headed
after the drop?
Not my concern.
Or yours.
Hey, so what's
in the crate, huh?
I hear it's toilet paper
for general MacArthur.
So why'd you join
the marines?
To kill people.
Your requested cereal,
chief.
Hey, Lindy here
has a confession to make.
This asshole wanted
to join the army.
But he ended up in the Navy,
and he doesn't know how to swim.
I'll tell him tell him why
he doesn't need to know
how to swim.
Because we won't be going
in the water, sir?
Hey, son, you any idea
how old the ship is?
It's 13 years old.
13 is an unlucky number.
We have the unlucky privilege
of carrying god knows what
with no protection
across the ocean.
So you don't need to swim
because if you go in the drink,
and the japs don't get you...
Here... the sharks will.
Sharks, sir?
Si, señor,
the great white shark.
Very top of the food chain.
No natural enemies,
an ancient killer left over
from the dinosaur age
when there was still a big
food supply in the water.
Go that way, you guys.
Now up on the land
by some evolutionary accident,
we developed these big brains,
and we invented weapons.
So we got used to being
at the top of the food chain,
but once you step
in that saltwater,
right back to the bottom
of the food chain.
Even if you swim well,
we look pathetic to sharks.
They think were wounded,
split up the middle, you know?
Five rows of dagger-like
teeth and jaws...
That can bend steel.
It's okay. Apparently,
we're not good eatin'.
'Course, they don't know that
until they shred us up pretty good
and we're bleeding
everywhere
and nothing turns a shark
on more...
Than blood.
- Sorry.
- Yeah.
I was sent down here
for an engine room punch.
- Xo send you?
- Yes, chief.
Yeah?
Look at that nose.
Look at that nose!
Look at it.
You can be thankful
you didn't get an engine room punch
- in the nose.
- Y-yes, chief.
I wouldn't worry
about it, though.
Our luck will hold
as long as we have
our little white dove of peace here.
She's our good luck charm.
All right, back to work!
Captain wants the boat
at top speed.
Chief, doves have longer
tail feathers.
That's a pigeon.
I know. My father
raises pigeons.
Hmm.
We accomplished our mission,
reaching tinian in record time
with zero casualties.
I fear the cargo
we were dropping off
could change
the nature of war forever.
Our next assignment
would be to return to combat,
but we were still
being denied our escort
♪
To the best chaplain
we ever had!
♪ For he's
a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ for he's
♪ for he's a
jolly good fellow ♪
♪ which nobody can deny. ♪
Congrats on
your last tour, chaps.
Thanks, boys.
I think I'm gonna take this one back
in my quarters.
Come on, short timer,
stay with us.
I do appreciate deuce
for not sneaking
any unclothed women
in here tonight.
Listen up, standish
is on the prowl, all right?
So keep it down.
Alvin, I know
that's tough for you.
Hey, I'm innocent as a dove,
father, you know me.
Thanks, fellas.
Admiral, I understand that
we are to sail to Leyte.
Now that we have
delivered the packages,
can we please
have our escort?
Charlie, how can you
have an escort?
You were never here.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Listen up,
listen up,
hey, hey,
who am I? Huh? Huh?
Hey! I'll have y'all know...
That I graduated second in
my class at the naval academy!
Whoo!
And I'm going to turn you into lean,
mean fighting machines!
Attention on deck!
Signalman!
Where did you
get that alcohol?
It's actually mine.
Is that so?
And that liquor on his breath?
Is that yours, too?
Swab up that giggle water.
We're shipping out!
There will be no Liberty!
We're received our orders.
And you'll all be on mess hall duty
effective immediately.
This isn't a minstrel show.
This is the United States Navy!
And I graduated first
in my class, by the way.
What in the hell?
That ain't your bag.
No, it's Alvin's.
I think he took the ring.
Hey, you're gonna
get busted.
I checked Sanchez and west.
Nothing. Shit.
Hey, thanks for helping me
out the other night with standish.
Wouldn't want you
to jeopardize your promotion.
All right, look,
the whole reason
that this ship is on a course
is 'cause they charted a plan
and they followed it.
So it's lucky Clara
didn't get a chance to say yes
because I'm incapable
of making a plan,
incapable of supporting her.
I'm just saying maybe things
turned out for the best.
My plan is to find
the son of a bitch that stole my ring
and marry her the second
i get off this ship,
and I don't care
what her parents or you
or anybody else
has got to say...
You the kid
that does the diving?
Oh, you mean the all-knowing
Brian smithwick?
Yeah, that's him.
Yeah, I do a little diving.
Okay, man, we want
to know about sharks.
I've been telling
Lindy here that sharks
don't really bother you
unless you're bleeding.
If you're bleeding,
it's a problem.
I get nosebleeds.
Captain's on the bridge.
Captain, some of the men
are sleeping on deck again.
Let them.
Their racks
are hotter than Hades.
- Visibility?
- Just this side of poor, sir,
got a fog rolling in.
Let's get through this weather
as quickly as possible.
Cease zigzagging until the fog clears,
full speed ahead.
- Aye aye.
- Standish.
Full speed ahead.
Full speed ahead, boys.
I hear you put 24 men
on mess hall duty for a week.
Yes, sir, I'm gonna
write them all up as well.
The Japanese are extremely
disciplined adversary, sir.
If we are to defeat them...
Sometimes it's better
to be respected than feared.
- D'Antonio.
- What?
Night watch
is that way.
- He took the ring.
- What?
The engagement ring,
deuce took it
when he pulled me
out of the fight,
- pickpocketing son of a bitch.
- Come on, deuce?
Ugh, you smell like
a distillery.
Might as well go on and admit.
You was scared, boy.
Scared? Of you?
You hit like a girl.
Next time I'm scared of a fight,
it'll be the first damn time.
Boy, you better be glad them mps
saved your ass from us.
Else we have to take you
like this chicken bone here.
Hey, Mr. big talk,
whatever you do
to that there
flight deck buzzard bone,
that's exactly what
I'm going to do to you
when I get out of his cage
and I catch you alone.
You suck that bone
like you've done that before!
Lady luck
is a friend of mine.
Open up
and let it shine. Huh?
Yeah.
- Come on, now,
- here we go, we go.
Ah, yeah, doc.
Okay.
Yeah. Mmm.
Deuce, where's my ring?
- What the hell you talking about?
- Oh, no, you know exactly
- what I'm talking about!
- No, I don't know what you're talking about!
Double or nothing!
Hey!
Oh, my god!
General quarters!
Out of the way!
Report!
All comms are down, sir!
I tried to stop the engines!
- But I don't know if the signal went through!
- Stay calm.
Cavanaugh,
keep trying to get through.
Standish, I want eyes
on the damage.
You heard the captain!
Go! Go!
Fire control, fire control now!
Hoses, starboard side.
Get that fire out!
Shut the engines down!
Shut them down!
Are we getting through?
Radios are down,
but I Jerry-rigged the wires.
- You sent the sos out?
- Yes sir.
Look at the needles.
They're moving.
Good work. Carry on.
Don't touch it
with your hands!
I told you not to touch it!
Come on, come on,
come on, come on!
We gotta go.
We gotta go!
USS Indianapolis trying to
establish any and all contact.
- Does anybody copy?
- Anything?
I don't know, sir.
- Keep trying.
- Yes, sir.
- Damage control.
- It's dead, sir.
This is USS Indianapolis.
Does anybody copy?
This is USS Indianapolis trying
to establish any contact.
Indianapolis, Indianapolis,
do you copy?
This is Leyte.
- What's going on?
- Three calls, sir.
One caller identified
himself as the captain.
- I dispatched three tugboats...
- On whose command?
Pull them back!
We don't send anyone out
until we get confirmation of their position.
That could be an enemy sub
trying to draw us out.
- Is that understood?
- Yes, sir.
We're not going to be able
to fight this one off.
She's going down.
Pass the word!
Abandon ship.
Abandon ship!
Help me, father.
I hear you.
Help me, father!
I'm scared.
Abandon ship,
abandon ship!
Captain's orders,
- Grab the documents, now!
- Aye aye, sir.
All hands on deck!
Abandon ship!
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on!
I've got the keys!
Come on, help me, too!
Help me, too!
Come on! Come on!
The keys, I dropped the keys!
I can't find them!
Hey!
No, no, no, no, no!
Hey, you can't leave me here!
Please come back!
Please!
Go. Watch out,
watch out, watch out.
Let's go, let's go!
Come on, let's go,
let's go! Let's go!
Please! Come back!
Please! Help!
Garrison, please!
You gotta come back, man!
Come on, let's go!
Garrison, please help me!
Come back, man! Help!
Bama,
toss the documents!
He said,
he gave the order.
Help!
Help me with the raft!
Garrison! Garrison!
Get the keys, man.
You gotta get me
out here, man.
Hold the light!
Get the keys!
Garrison, hurry up!
- I got it.
- Gimme.
Come on.
Were locked in!
Abandon ship!
Swim away from the ship
as fast as you can
as soon as you hit the water.
Try to see stay clear
of the oil.
Cavanaugh, jump!
That is in order!
The ship's breaking.
Listen.
I'm sorry!
Pray with me.
Our father who art
in heaven...
You should have left me here.
I'm sorry, man.
I'm sorry I got you killed.
I'm sorry.
Thy will be done.
♪
Go, go!
Go, jump! Jump!
Hello?
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
Hello?
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
Paul?
Paul.
Keep your head up.
Come on.
Kick with me, now.
Kick with me.
Kick with me. There you go.
Come on, man!
Keep your head up.
Oh, god.
This is not safe.
We got to get to the rafts.
Sir, are you crazy?
We can't leave this thing.
This thing's sinking.
That's an order.
No.
Get Lindy in the raft.
- Get him up.
- Come on, guys.
Like this.
What sunk us?
It had to have been the japs.
They might still be a out there
looking to finish this off.
- Did the signal go out?
- It had to.
Someone will know
we're missing.
They'll come rescue us, boys.
They'll come rescue us.
You guys okay?
The captain make it?
He went down
with the ship.
Attention, men!
Attention!
If you are able-bodied
and in a raft, get out now!
The rafts are for
injured men and officers!
Bring all of the provisions
over here now!
- Grab my hand!
- I need help over here!
Now!
Get out of the raft!
Let the injured men
into the raft now!
Hold on.
Captain.
Hey, you made it.
Campbell.
Medicine.
I need it.
Hey... you made it,
captain, you made it.
You got some morphine,
huh? Hey.
You made it.
Okay... ah.
Ain't this a hell
of a damn note?
Gotta keep the leg elevated!
Keep it elevated!
Okay.
Don't go nowhere.
Sir, please
don't go nowhere.
- I'm not going.
- Don't go nowhere. Please don't go nowhere.
- How's my little boy?
- He's good.
- Yeah.
- He's strong, like his daddy.
He is? Don't go nowhere.
Don't leave me here.
I'm not.
I'm not leaving you.
What I'm saying, fireplug,
is if you gotta
leave a woman,
you always make sure
she thinks she left you.
Yeah? And how do
you do that?
That requires
a level of sophistication
you have not yet
acquired, my friend.
Calm down!
Save your energy!
You too good
to flag a plane, sir?
Oh, you think me waving
would've made the difference?!
I'll kill you!
- I will have you court-martialed, sailor!
- Go ahead!
If we get rescued...
And if we get rescued...
Let's all cool off!
We're going to get rescued soon.
These men look to us on how
to conduct themselves.
We need each other.
I need to get the life
jacket off the doctor.
Father, bless his soul,
in the name of the father,
son, and holy ghost.
How much longer are we going
to circle, an hour, a day?
Keep looking.
It's nine men lost on one plane,
lieutenant.
It's beyond a needle
in a haystack.
Even with coordinates,
we barely have enough fuel
to get back to base.
Do you copy?
You got eyes
on that plane?
That's a negative, sir.
Request a few
more beats out here.
Negative, you've been
out there too long as it is.
Bring it back.
This way,
right over here.
Just grab on.
Quinn...
Your head looks like
40 miles of bad road.
We gotta get you
in the raft.
Unh-unh, no.
Not with him, no.
Keep playing.
Theo, what in the hell you
writing in that book now, boy?
"Dear mama, I should've
learned how to swim.
But now my black ass
gonna drown."
What are you all laughing at,
huh?
We're all gonna die,
you know?
You know that, right?
I mean, the funny part is
you mess hall boys are dying for a country
that doesn't give a shit
about you or your people.
Yeah, well,
i ain't waiting for no white folks
or anybody else
to care for me.
I just knew the streets
of Detroit wouldn't.
I'm telling you, man,
I'd have died out there.
Same here.
The streets of galveston
killed my pa and my little brother.
Plus I wanted to get out
and see the world,
chase some foreign tail.
I second that.
Hey, you take notes.
Adventure, sex...
You put that in your book,
it'll sell like hot cakes.
We might even have
a new new testament!
What's going on
over there!
Get in the raft!
Get the men out of the water!
Get on the raft!
Everybody out of the water!
Get out of the water!
You men, out of the water!
What are you doing?
You stop swimming,
you get out of the water!
Where in the hell's
he going?
What happened?
May the lord bless you
and keep you.
May he shine
his face upon you.
Amen.
Dear god, take my soul...
Thank you, god.
Agh! Get off me,
god damn it!
- There's something out there!
- Sharks!
Theodore, Theodore,
have you see any other group?
I was in a big group,
100 or more of us.
- Which direction?
- That way!
Son of a bitch!
Peel that open
and inject him.
I'll just head out
a little ways.
I won't be gone long.
See if I can find them.
No, wait, captain!
Don't leave us!
Talk to him, distract him!
- Keep him calm!
- Wait, sir!
Sir! Captain!
Help me.
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪ how sweet the sound ♪
♪ that saved ♪
♪ a wretch ♪
♪ like me ♪
♪ I once was lost... ♪
It's okay...
Oh, Christ have mercy on me!
"He wandered into the mess hall
gleam in his eyes,
rolled the dice, and said,
'lady luck is a friend of mine.
Open up and let it shine.'"
- what are you doing?
- I'm reading.
- What?
- Reading!
You're gonna have to do better than that.
I'm fucking dying!
Okay, okay!
- Do better than that.
- I'm sorry!
"The first time I saw her,
it was on market street
in San Francisco.
You could spot
her red dress a mile away."
Was it a tight dress or what?
Sure, sure,
tight dress.
So tight, leaving little
to the imagination.
Did you write that?
Yeah, it's my book.
That's good.
Read it again.
"The first time I saw..."
Sir, please, stay with me.
I'm going to read you,
I'm going to read you, okay?
Okay?
"She was so...
She was safe.
She knew.
I will not be
defined by what I face,
but how I face it."
"It was as if she was
a fallen angel,"
chief mcwhorter:
Angel in the skies?
"Sent to watch over him.
'Kiss me with your eyes, '
she teased.
Every molecule in this sailor's
body ached for her touch."
Tie us together!
Found more men
and supplies.
These two say
they drifted away
from the same group
as you, Theodore.
How you men doing?
This young man
is telling a story,
making this old sailor blush,
mcvay.
So go on, man,
does he take her or what?
Carry on.
"'I'll give you all the love
this life allows, '
she whispered,
and with that,
she spread herself beneath him,
finally guiding him home."
"Dearest Louise,
it's been two days at sea
and no sign of rescue.
I fear I have
let the men down.
I try to find little things
to give them hope."
- Spam.
- "But even that is in short supply."
House specialty.
God damn.
This...
Baboon ass...
Tastes like
a two-inch steak.
We'll open one can a day.
Splash some seawater
on your head,
let the breeze
cool you down.
Don't drink it.
It'll make you crazy.
"It is bordering on impossible
that a plane would spot us.
But still,
at the slightest sound,
I look up to the sky."
♪
Shut up a minute.
Why, that old tightwad!
He'd steal flies
from a blind spider!
Yeah, well,
he just died
and left you
$500,000 bucks.
$500,000?
I taught her
a couple of dance moves.
Man...
She sure can dance.
Clara's the cutest
thing, man.
Do you know what she
used to call me, bama?
No.
I don't want to hear it.
I told you,
not in the raft,
shitbird!
What the hell?
Stop! Stop!
You ain't scaring 'em off!
You're ringing
the dinner bell.
I couldn't use my Annapolis
ring as a fishing lure
because we need it
for good luck,
but I could use
my wedding ring,
because my wife
would understand.
You see,
she likes to fish.
Might even like it
more than I do.
How'd you guys meet?
You aren't going
to use this
for one of your creative
stories, are you?
No, sir.
At the Chevy chase club
outside of Washington, DC.
The band was playing
"pennies from heaven,"
and I saw her.
She was singing to herself.
She's everything to me.
Well, I'm sure you miss
your family, too.
Have you ever told her?
How you just told me?
Told her what?
How you feel about her.
I try to write to her.
Words don't come
even easily for me...
Not yet! God!
I got a little boy I never seen!
No! No angels!
No, no angels!
Please, please, god!
Hold it tight.
Don't let me die here
without seeing him!
- Hold my hand.
- I don't wanna die!
Don't let me die
without letting me see my...
♪
Captain. Captain?
It's okay.
The fleet is coming.
Get some rest.
Attention!
If anyone
was coming to save us,
they would've
been here by now.
An island has been spotted
a few miles away.
That's impossible.
We're somewhere
in the philippine sea.
You don't know
where we are.
We're going to catch
a current,
and we're gonna ride it over
to that island.
The captain would want us
to stay together.
The captain is dead,
you understand?
I am in charge now.
I need a few good men
who are tired of being
shark bait to join me now!
You, come on over.
Obviously, we can't take
anyone who's bleeding.
I'm sorry, chap.
I promised my mama
I'd come home safe.
Come on, men,
swim on over.
And, waxman, I'm going to leave you
in charge of the wounded.
And those two
troublemakers over there
you seem to have such
an affinity for.
What about leaving us
some supplies? Sir.
Oh, we'll leave you
with that extra raft,
don't you worry.
We'll send help.
What about you, marine?
I'm will stay
with the padre.
Very well, then.
Everybody grab an oar.
Let's paddle.
All in unison now, let's go.
I know we're tired.
The island's over there.
All right, god bless.
Row! Row! Come on, men!
Mike?
Mike!
Mike, are you out there?!
We're here!
Bama, bama, wake up,
they're here. Bama!
- What?
- We're getting out of here.
They're here.
That's Clara! That's Clara!
That's Clara!
Calm down! Hey, hey!
You're just hallucinating.
Calm down.
Hey, calm down.
You're just hallucinating.
Calm down, buddy.
I love her, Mike.
I love Clara!
I always have.
Since Sunday school
at first baptist, and...
And I... I was gonna
make something of myself.
What's that?
Gotta be sharks!
Get in the raft! Get in the raft!
It's gonna flip.
Go on the other side.
Damn, that stinks man.
Probably been dead
for a good two hours or so.
Go on, take his vest.
Oh, jeez,
that's the kid, Theodore.
That's his book, man.
Shark took his
poor head clean off.
You think it's just luck,
who lives and who dies?
It was his time.
I'm hoping that
I'm too bad for heaven
and too good for hell.
I think people
make up religion
to make themselves
feel better.
Can't be a god,
not with the stuff
that I seen.
At least,
not one that cares.
Death, evil...
I saw a man sacrifice
his life for another man.
I ain't telling you
what to believe, brother.
I... I just know there's
a lot of good in the world,
and...
I want to get back to it.
- You said your girl?
- Mm-hmm.
Is it true she's the
Michigan state arm wrestling champion?
Two years in a row.
Don't get
out of line with her.
Do you think this is going
to mess up my dance game?
Well...
It's called the Lindy hop.
What if she doesn't believe
i bought her a ring?
Then you'll get her another one.
And you'll give it to her.
She's great...
A great girl, right?
Take care of her.
- What?
- Promise me, bam.
Take care of her.
Hey, you stop.
Listen, bam,
remember on the ship?
You told me to slow down.
I didn't listen.
And I grabbed the hatch.
I burned my hands, bam.
Melted my skin.
I never listen.
You were doing what you thought
you were supposed to be doing.
And I got her in trouble.
That's why...
The ring.
A nice girl like that.
Mike? Mike?
Mike?
Hey.
Don't be dead.
Hey, we got company.
West.
They're all dead.
Standish. Cavanaugh.
Sharks everywhere.
West, you're okay.
Forgive me, chap.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- You're safe.
- I'm so sorry.
You're safe.
No!
Get out of the water!
Swim! Swim!
Get out!
No!
God damn it!
"It is the fourth day,
and many men
have simply given up.
I've seen the strongest boys,
their lives full of promise,
succumb to our horrible
circumstances.
Others of us feel as though
we are losing our minds."
♪
Garrison.
Garrison, is that...
Is that a hallucination?
That son of a bitch is close.
Can you see it?
Do you see that?
Help!
Over here! Over here!
I can't see.
I ca... I can't see.
I can't see any...
I can't see anything.
Wave right here.
He's close.
- Hey!
- Hey! Hey!
I'm getting nothing
but static, sir.
It's that antenna.
I thought you had it looked at.
I did.
God damn it.
Look down!
We're above something.
I think it's an oil spill
from a Japanese sub.
Let's circle back.
Get ready to drop.
He saw us!
Drop below 50!
Hang on!
Are you sure it was
a Japanese submarine, sir?
Who else would be out here?
You got eyes on this?
On my go!
Are you...
Seeing this, skipper?
You seeing...
Seeing this?
It doesn't see us.
Sees the oil.
And drop
in three, two, one.
Wait! Wait!!
There's got to be 100 men out
there spread out over miles.
Get on the radio now!
Hey, look,
this is gambler 17.
We are flying over hundreds
of boys in the water.
I repeat, we are flying
over hundreds of boys in the water.
Amber 17, copy this.
We have to follow protocol.
The Japanese
could be out there.
Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
Sir, lieutenant!
Lieutenant, sir!
We just got a call in.
There's something
in the water.
Could be the plane
we're looking for, sir.
Find all the water we have,
food, too, medical supplies.
God knows how long
they've been down there.
Do you see what I see?
There are men everywhere!
The japs must have
sunk a ship.
Japs might
still be out there
waiting to sink any ship
that comes along!
Those boys need help now.
Sir, request position
permission for a no-no.
Negative!
Do not land that plane
on open ocean!
You can't risk
that kind of damage.
I'm gonna land this plane.
Land the damn plane,
lieutenant.
Hang on!
Holy shit, these guys
are doing a water landing.
Were almost out of fuel, sir.
We have to go.
10-4,
heading back to base.
He saw us!
♪
Taking on water!
Holy shit.
- Pick up the single swimmers.
- Lieutenant,
wouldn't it be faster
to pick up the ones in groups?
It'd be a hell
of a lot faster,
but they stand a better chance
of survival in big groups.
Hey, son, what's your name?
What happened here?
Brian smithwick.
Signalman first class aboard
the USS Indianapolis.
Even out!
Straight!
Lieutenant,
the cabin's getting full.
Get some more on the wing.
Don't forget this tail.
We can put some on there.
Watch that cleat!
We're going home!
Are you serious...
Hey, wait, wait!
It's our skipper.
Thank you...
For... landing!
We got room
for a few more.
I'm okay!
Get my men...
Out of the water!
It's the USS Indianapolis.
That can't be.
It shouldn't be,
but it is.
This is a class-a
clusterfuck.
Somebody is gonna
pay for this.
If I were you,
I'd send every ship you got
before the sharks
get at the rest of them.
I don't know how many more
i fit on this plane.
You're putting them
on the plane?
You'll never get off
the water!
You kidding me?
The plane's shot, hoss. It's shot to shit.
We're taking on water.
We're lucky to be afloat.
You don't want to consider
sending a ship for these boys,
send one for me.
"I don't understand
why it took so long.
At last relief came.
There wasn't enough room
on the plane
for all the survivors,
but soon the ships followed,
the bassett,
the ringness, the Talbot,
the register,
the dulfilho,
and the Cecil j. Doyle."
That's exactly
what I want.
Our hero ship that delivered
the bomb in record time
got sunk four days ago.
What?
How many survived?
317.
879 men lost their lives.
Command screwed the pooch
on three sos calls
from the Indianapolis.
That's not including
an intercepted message
from the Japanese i-58
that did that sinking.
Son of a bitch.
The Japanese
on the verge of surrender,
and that's due in part
to the Indianapolis.
I don't want to hear about
the sinking in the press
till I'm damn good and ready.
Jap surrender
we'll just mention in a news dump.
Bury it below
some positive news.
There will still be
an investigation.
Too many lives were lost.
With the Pearl harbor
inquiry going on,
now ain't the time
to be raising questions
about military incompetence.
Or you just suggest
we indict the big blue dick.
No, I'm saying the press
and the public
will want somebody's
head on a platter.
Then we'll give
'em someone.
I want to go home!
I just want to go home!
Where's the doctor?!
I need a doctor!
Just lie back, sir.
- Signalman.
- Yes, sir.
Did your friend make it?
The boy you jumped over with?
"Through some terrible
twist of fate,
it turns out that I am
one of the only officers
that survived.
Many of those that died
were our dear friends.
It will be a tremendous
burden for you
to have to tell their wives
that all their husbands
perished
while yours,
the captain, lived."
Anybody seen Cavanaugh?
Did Cavanaugh
make it?
What about standish?
Garrison,
9:00. 9:00.
Stick your hand out.
It's Theodore, you dummy.
You little turd!
We found your book
on a dead guy, man.
I gave it to a sailor
for comfort.
I ain't ready to go down
god's toilet bowl yet.
I missed you guys!
I found that...
In the gutter...
Two weeks ago.
You believe that?
Thanks.
Don't... don't thank me.
I was going to come here.
I was going to tell you that
i didn't know whose it was.
But I knew.
I knew it was d'Antonio's.
I was gonna pawn it
to pay some debt.
I'm not just like some
everyday normal kind of asshole, bama.
I'm a special kind.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
The war is over.
Atomic bombs have been dropped
on Hiroshima and Nagasaki,
and Japan has surrendered
to the allied powers.
"The packages we delivered
worked
with devastating accuracy.
The men of the USS Indianapolis
returned home..."
A joyous day indeed.
Tickertape parades
are the order of the day
for all our brave
American gis,
both those who came back
and those courageous boys
who have given their lives.
"Not all of them
with good news."
"For them,
the war was over."
Mom!
♪
"But for me, the battle
was just beginning."
I'm here.
Mcwhorter:
My boy. My baby boy.
I'll never get to see him!
Mcvay residence.
I hope you burn in hell
for what you did.
Just hang up, Charlie.
Burn in hell!
We need you back, Charlie.
Me, your boy...
We need you.
A lot of boys needed me.
You did all you could.
I hear you got your promotion.
I turned it down.
I'm moving to Washington, DC,
going to law school.
Might even help my uncle
on his next campaign.
Well, I wish you
all the luck in the world, Brian.
You deserve it.
Clara, I, um...
I've been through
just about the scariest thing
that a man could face
out there on the ocean.
I don't know that
that's something
I'm ever
going to get over.
You see,
I've been afraid
to live my life
to the fullest.
I've been afraid a long time.
Afraid of what?
Just, well,
not being good enough.
Yeah.
About being rejected.
Rejected?
By who?
By you, Clara.
I have been in love with you
since the day that we met.
And I, um...
Marriage?
Brian...
Mike and I are having...
A baby, yeah, I know.
But you see,
Mike was like a brother to me,
and that baby
is going to need a father.
And so I would be honored
if you would at least
consider being my wife.
You don't gotta love me back
or anything like that.
And we might never
be as rich as your folks.
But we could start
a fresh life in DC.
I know you already
got one ring,
but I thought maybe
two was better than one.
After all he's been through,
they're putting him on trial.
Sounds like they're
looking for a scapegoat.
Louise, it...
It's complicated.
What's complicated?
Admiral.
Captain.
Would you gentlemen
like some tea?
Thank you, Louise.
Bumped into the submarine,
which had fired
the torpedoes.
Members of the
tanker's crew related...
The president
withheld immediate comment...
Charlie, as far as
they were concerned,
you were on a secret mission
under the command
of the president.
And since their orders were
to never announce arrivals,
they'll argue that they
were not supposed to announce
non-arrivals either.
So what now?
I found outside counsel.
What I'm about
to tell you...
Can't ever
leave this room.
Four days before your ship
was sunk by the Japanese...
There was another us ship
in those same waters.
The USS underhill.
She was torpedoed...
And sunk.
Point being, you should
have had an escort.
You should have had sonar.
Charlie, I am so sorry.
The trial
will be in Washington.
This one right here, fellas,
is to being back
on solid ground.
To never seeing another shark again.
To wishing our captain luck
in this bullshit trial.
To all the good men
we lost at sea.
- Amen.
Excuse me, boys.
See something
you like, Alvin?
Oh, no, yeah, no I...
I recognize
one of those rings.
But, uh, not the other one.
I got it
from my husband, bama.
Your husband.
Oh.
You got something
you want to say, Alvin?
Isn't that d'Antonio's girl?
Yeah, she was. So?
I mean,
a fella married
his buddy's
pregnant girlfriend?
That's...
Well, he's
a better man than me.
Yeah, I'll drink to that.
Hey, mcvay's trial starts
at 0900.
Think we ought a be there
about an hour early.
Sir! Sir!
Are you expecting
to be court martialed?
Sir, answer the question!
Do you feel
personally responsible
for the loss
of your men? Captain!
Captain mcvay,
you're being accused
of hazarding your ship
by failing to zigzag
as an evasive maneuver
and failing to abandon ship
in a timely manner.
For the benefit of the court,
how do you plead?
Not guilty.
And when the ship was hit,
did you hear any directives
from your captain?
I went to the bridge.
Commander Cavanaugh was there.
He told me
that captain mcvay
had given the order
to abandon ship.
But you never got the order
from captain mcvay.
- Not initially, but...
- Thank you, sir, that'll suffice.
No further questions,
your honor.
Why didn't you object?
That was military protocol.
Captain mcvay,
what, pray tell,
is your theory
on zigzagging?
Not so effective
against kaitens,
it's a new Japanese weapon
a manned suicide torpedo,
like an underwater
kamikaze plane.
Hard to hit
what you can't see.
And on that night?
Let's get through this weather
is quickly as possible.
Cease zigzagging
until the fog clears.
Full speed ahead.
Tell us about
the sequence of events
the night you were struck.
We'd been hit.
The question was how bad.
The Indianapolis
is a strong ship.
She's built
like a floating tank.
We had survived
multiple attacks before
so we had
to assess the damage.
- General quarters!
- We had no electrical.
Did you get the sos out?
Pass the word!
Abandon ship.
So you called abandon ship
about six to eight minutes
- after you were struck.
- Abandon ship!
How did you personally
abandon ship?
Go, go!
Can anyone hear me?
Paul?
Paul.
It was the last
i saw of my men that night
and the last I saw
of our ship.
Nothing further,
your honor.
We wish to call to the stand
the only submarine commander
who is relevant to this case
because he was there.
The United States government
calls captain hashimoto
of the imperial Japanese Navy.
Order in the court.
Captain hashimoto,
you understand
that you are under oath
to tell the truth,
the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth.
But you're not Christian,
are you?
Shintoist.
We believe that the soul
exists after death,
and, yes,
i understand the difference
between truth
and falsehood.
Very well.
Tell us about your actions
on the night in question.
Did you fire your kaitens?
So the USS Indianapolis
was sunk
using conventional torpedoes.
Yes.
In your opinion,
if the ship had been zigzagging,
would it have made
a difference?
No.
We were too close.
I fired six torpedoes.
He had no chance to escape.
No further questions,
your honor.
Mcvay must pay!
Call to order.
Please rise.
On the first count,
failure to give the order
to abandon ship
in a timely manner,
we find the defendant,
captain Charles Butler
mcvay III, not guilty.
What does that mean?
What happened?
They only announce
the not-guilty verdicts.
He's been found guilty
of hazarding the ship
by failing to zigzag.
They court-martial
our captain
and didn't mention
all of our dead?
They should be building
him a monument.
Charlie,
i want you to know,
I'd rather this
played out differently.
Hundreds of ships
were sunk during the war,
and yours is the only
court-martial?
It stinks.
Thank you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Who's that guy?
Who is that guy?
I need a few minutes alone.
Captain...
Captain, how do you feel
about this being the worst
naval disaster in history?
- Captain...
- Is it true you were denied your choice of an attorney?
This would never happen
in Japan.
If the roles were reversed,
you would not be called in
to testify on anyone's behalf.
Was there anything
i could have done?
You were exposed.
We were there.
As a commander
in the imperial Japanese Navy,
it was my duty to kill you.
But as a man...
I have regrets.
I had a good idea
of what we were carrying.
I, too, did my duty.
But as a man...
I find no...
Honor in it.
I often wonder
how things would be
if I had stopped you before
you completed your mission.
We have learned to
forgive each other as former adversaries.
Perhaps one day...
We can forgive ourselves
as men.
They say we won the war.
In my opinion,
we'll really win
when there is no more war.
And just like there were
different groups
of survivors in the water...
There are different
groups on land today.
Every year,
we survivors gather together
to honor our fallen brothers.
Even though they're gone,
they'll be with us forever.
Our new mission
is to try to make sure
that even future generations
never forget
the price that
we all paid for freedom.
Time marched on,
and I eventually lost
my dear Louise.
And the memories...
Of all the boys
we lost at sea...
Never faded.
And the phone...
Never stopped ringing.
♪
The first day,
we must have had 120,
150 sharks around us
all day long.
It's a horrifying experience,
you know,
being in the water,
don't know if they're
coming to get you.
If you hit those sharks
in the eyeball,
it really hurt them,
and they left you alone,
and you could see down
in the water maybe 50 feet,
and they'd go down there
and just thrash
back and forth in pain.
Whenever they said there were
sharks in the area,
I always pulled my legs up
and froze.
And I was petrified.
I saw so many sharks
eating men
that I never will
like them.
You know,
i think they're horrible.
♪
Psagmeno.com
MOViE iNFO WiTH .srt FiLES!